Leonardo Piovesan

Software Engineer

Cascavel, State of Paraná, Brazil +55 (45) 99934-7911 leopvsn@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Looking for a remote opportunity where I can make good use of my skills, to thrive and grow with the company and as a professional, willing to learn any other language/stack/technology requested and doing my best to show how passionate I am about everything that we can build together.

SKILLS

- Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Vue.js, React Native, Redux, Vuex, Node.js, C, C#, .NET, Neo4j, Firebase, Firestore NoSql, MySql, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Grafana, HTML5, CSS3, StyledComponents, TailwindCSS GitHub, GitLab, Git, Azure, TFS, Figma, Linux, Docker, Arduino.
- Languages: fluent in Portuguese, advanced English and basic Spanish.
- Overall Knowledge: computers, Microsoft Office package, software development, design patterns, microservices, DB management, version control and testing frameworks.

EXPERIENCE

Qualicorp, Brazil - Full Stack Developer

JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

• Being one of the leading, full-service healthcare benefits administrators and health management services providers in Brazil, Qualicorp was founded in 1997 with the goal of expanding access to affordable private health plans to the general public. Aware of its size and importance, it was a heavy responsibility to cope and work with such sensitive data. I'm currently working as software developer who is mostly focused on the back-end, I've been able to deep-learn how to debug, had the opportunity to learn some growing relevant technology like Neo4j, with the company being one/if not the biggest latin-america client of its cloud database service.

 I've used mostly Node.js to develop and maintain the countless API's available in a microservices architecture, Neo4j and Oracle SQL database, Vue.js for the front-end, Azure for pipelines and TFS for repo/version control.

FugaPet, Brazil - Full Stack Developer

OCTOBER 2020 - MAY 2022

- The startup came with the purpose of protecting and finding lost pets. The app itself is free, offering some functionalities such as user registration, pet profiling, vaccination card where owners have access to a calendar and can opt to receive notifications of the next doses, pet shops and local stores, NGOs that take care of animals and display them for adoption, also displaying an option for donation, a map with a feed that lists the latest cases of missing pets, offering rewards as well. Besides that, we also have our own QR Code tags which offer some premium benefits and they can be scanned from any cell phone, no app needed, to send the pet location and some important data for the lost pet owners immediately.
- I've used mostly React Native, Expo, Styled Components to build the mobile application, React, Tailwind and Next on the website, as well as Node.js, Firebase for functions and Cloud Firestore Database for the back, Git and Gitlab for repo control.

Freelance, Brazil - Front End Developer
JAN 2019 - OCTOBER 2020

EDUCATION

Univel, Brazil - Systems Analysis and Development JANUARY 2020 - JANUARY 2023

 OS, threads, databases, algorithms, virtual machines, data structures, binary trees, pointers, dynamic memory allocation, recursion, hardware, network/communication protocols, software engineering, object oriented programming, UML, modeling, diagrams, use cases and software requirements, IT governance, agile methodologies such as Scrum, web development, web accessibility, testing tools, prototyping and vector graphics editors, software architecture, SOLID principles, design patterns.

 Some technologies that were used during graduation: Python, C, C#, .NET, Java, JavaScript, Jquery, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Arduino, Figma, Docker, VirtualBox, Cisco Packet Tracer, Astah, Jira, Delphi, FireMonkey.

UNIOESTE, Brazil - Computer Science

JANUARY 2015 - JANUARY 2017

• Algorithms, databases, C language.

PROFESSIONAL BACKGROUND

Vast experience on system analysis and development, gathering and establishing documentation, Microsoft Office package, UML diagrams and programming. In-depth experience in using a search engine and following documentation, working on a fast paced environment alongside agile methodologies, designing responsive layouts, prototyping, debugging, API's and endpoints, REST architecture, design patterns, SSG, SPA and SSR applications. Managing relational and non-relational databases.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATES

- Cambridge English: First (FCE) C1 2017.
- Triplebyte Engineering Certificate: Advanced React Knowledge 2022.
- Neo4j Certified Professional 2022.
- Udemy Web Development: HTML, CSS, SQL, PHP, JavaScript, Apache -2020.
- University Extension Project Mentes Pensantes: Arduino 2021.
- Hackathon Honorable Mention, Show Rural Coopavel 2022.
- Alura Functional Programming, Regex Regular Expressions, Webpack, HTTP/1.1, HTTP/2, Rest + Node.js, TypeScript - 2022.